M. ESAT OZEN

Full Stack Software Developer Greater Boston Area Massachusetts

(203) 278 6572 ozenesat@gmail.com https://ozenesat.github.io/ https://github.com/ozenesat https://linkedin.com/in/ozenesat

SKILLS

JavaScript React.js Node.js Next.js **Express** Mongoose Mango DB Ruby on Rails

SQL **PostgreSQL** Git/GitHub Phabricator jQuery **AJAX JSON** Handlebars HTML5 CSS Bootstrap Linux/Ubuntu

WORK STATUS

Green Card Holder

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Software Engineer *Immersive*

Middle East Technical University (METU) **Bachelor of Science**

Mathematics

Abstract Algebra Combinatorics

Complex Calculus

Cryptography

Discrete Mathematics

Introduction to C

Mathematical Analysis

Number Theory

Leadership

President of Student Council @ METU

SUMMARY

I'm a developer with a background in mathematics and experience in startups. I enjoy breaking down and solving complex problems with analytical thinking, while my work in startups has trained me to transfer innovate ideas into the code base. I'm excited to produce exceptional pieces of work that will have a direct positive impact on end-users.

EXPERIENCE

Rapic.io - Remote — Front-End Developer

May 2020 - Present

- Integrate the OAuth functionality into React application with back-end server.
- Working with a global dev team over Phabricator with scrum methodology.
- Design, implement and test the React application from scratch with Next.js.

General Assembly - Boston, MA — Software Engineer Immersive February 2020 - May 2020

- Completed a 12-week / 500+ hour immersive course on full-stack web development using a variety of modern programming languages and technologies.
- Developed full-stack SPA, Photo Collector, with the technologies React, OAuth, Bootstrap, Node, Express, MongoDB, with 3 party APIs.
- Worked in 4-day sprints while practicing Agile methodology, Scrum principles, and using MVC frameworks. Utilized Git and GitHub for version control.
- Individually and as a team developed seven full-stack web applications using the technologies JavaScript, React, ¡Query, ROR, PostgreSQL, Node, Express.
- Built quality RESTful APIs and integrated data from third-party APIs.

Ace It Education - Boston, MA — Web Developer

May 2019 - February 2020

- Created and maintained the two websites of the company with WordPress.
- Managed social media and website content. Advertised the events via Eventbrite and MailChimp.

The Fix - Farmington, CT — Stores Manager

May 2018 - May 2019

- · Managed the finances and personnel of the company's branches at four different locations. Scheduled the employee shifts and acted as Human Resources.
- Efficiently managed ~\$1 million yearly budget and increased profitability of the company by 10% with user and market research.
- Worked on improving sales strategies and customer satisfaction. Established the use of alternative products and services for customer needs.

Zaman Media Group - Ankara, Turkey — Correspondent

May 2014 - April 2016

- · Worked with editors and senior correspondents as a team to cover all of the latest political news from the Capitol. Reported judicial news from the courts.
- · Acted as the assistant to the Executive Officer in Ankara headquarters of the media outlet.